Parker Lougheed

parlough.dev

GitHub

github.com/parlough

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/parkerlougheed

Email

parkerlougheed@gmail.com

Software Engineer Educator && Advocate

I am a software engineer and educator with years of experience working with teams and in a variety of specializations with a passion for open source development and facilitating instructional experiences. I am particularly attracted to teaching computing, as well as the implementation of tools to more easily facilitate this.

Outside of computing, I have a passion for education of all types and moving pedagogy in general forward through technology.

I'm also progressing as a Chinese learner, resulting in an increased interest in the accessibility of instruction and surrounding tools for non-English speakers and English learners when learning computing and software engineering.

Education

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign | *Jan 2022 - May 2023* Master of Education in Curriculum & Instruction - Digital Learning

University of Wisconsin - Madison | Sep 2017 - May 2020 Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Employment

Independent Contractor | Apr 2021 - Present

Working with Google, handling issue triage, pull request review, dev work, and technical writing for various Dart and Flutter websites.

PerBlue Entertainment | Software Engineer | May 2022 - Aug 2022

Worked as a software engineer intern working on the backend and related integration on a mobile tower defense game.

UW - Madison CS Department | Peer Mentor | Sep 2021 - May 2022

Worked as a peer mentor for an introductory data science course: creating projects, giving lectures, hosting labs, and holding office hours.

Epic Systems | Software Developer | Jun 2020 - Apr 2021

Worked as a software developer creating a self-service data analytics tool for the healthcare industry.

UW - Madison CS Department | Peer Mentor | Sep 2019 - May 2020

Worked as a peer tutor and mentor for computer science courses: creating assignments, grading scripts, instructional videos, and helping students.

iD Tech Camps | Lead Instructor | Summer 2019

Worked as the lead instructor for the UW-Madison location, teaching students of various ages and levels programming.

Skills and Experience

General

Static Analysis, Compilers, Teaching, Systems Programming, Operating Systems, OOP, PL Design, Open Source, Code Review, Game Development, Chinese, Remote Collaboration, Content Creation

Educational

Concept-Based Curriculum, Assignment Creation, Technical Writing, Game-Based Learning, Computer-Assisted Grading, Teaching ESL Students, Education Technology, Personalized Learning, Scaffolding

Programming Languages

Dart, Java, Kotlin, JavaScript, TypeScript, C#, C, Python, Rust, M

Development Frameworks and Libraries

Flutter, Solid, Lit, Angular, React, ASP.NET, ASM, OpenGL

Development Tooling and Software

Git, Unix, SQL, CI/CD, Gerrit, SVN, Gradle, Maven, Node, Decompilers, Jetbrains IDEs, Google Cloud, Visual Studio, Unity